JOHN HECKBERT

FINANCIAL WEB DEVELOPMENT PROFESSIONAL

After leaving a 10 year successful career as a high-performance technology professional optimizing, managing and selling IT services, technology solutions and service delivery across a broad spectrum of industries to create a new business opportunity coaching families suffering from debt in effective money management techniques, it is now time to bring these money management coaching techniques and other financial literacy teachings to the web. Security of person and financial information of paramount concern building on previous experience.

Core Competencies

Personal Coaching ◆ B2B & B2C Sales & Marketing ◆ Lead Generation ◆ Relationship Builiding
Financial Management ◆ Budget Management ◆ Staff Training ◆ SEO ◆ MVC ◆ BDD/TDD
Social Media Marketing ◆ Team Leadership ◆ Process Management ◆ Strategic Planning ◆ ITIL
HTML ◆ CSS ◆ Javascript ◆ React ◆ Axios ◆ mySQL ◆ Express ◆ Sendgrid ◆ Emailjs ◆ SASS
Camunda ◆ Oauth ◆ Sequelize ◆ GitHub ◆ JIRA ◆ Fortran ◆ REXX ◆ Wordpress ◆ Linux ◆ Windows
macOS ◆ Project Management ◆ Recruiting ◆ IBM/AOC ◆ Netview ◆ Cisco ◆ HP-OpenView

Portfolio available at johnheckbert.com

Selected Career Highlights

- Developed and executed the business development strategy that produced over \$1 million in new business proposals within only 6 months for a professional services/management consulting firm
- Established the business development vision, marketing approach, and sales channel strategy for a new network services company and secured 10 orders valued at over \$200,000 within the first 7 weeks
- Extensive leadership experience managing teams, optimizing enterprise-level support functions, and improving service delivery for leaders in the Communications, Utilities, and Insurance sectors

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Web Developer / Consultant

2014 - 2020

♦ Auteur Group ◆

- Helped small business clients create a web presence by designing and developing custom websites and SEO tactics
- Conceived, organized and conducted a social media campaign, called "Five for the Drive", to promote local businesses impacted by a major, delayed infrastructure project
- Tools included: Apache, Wordpress, mySQL, HTML, CSS, Node, Express, Oauth, automation tools, APIs for Twitter, Facebook, Instagram and others

Mortgage Broker 2009 - 2020

Mortgage Alliance Accumetrix ◆ Mortgage Intelligence ◆ CIBC ◆ Finbank Mortgage and Finance

- Generated over \$60 million in new mortgage origination
- Maximized the tool set available to help First Home Buyers to purchase and pay off their home purchase sooner by leveraging strategies developed as a credit coach with the Paladin Program
- Revised the financial literacy coaching program that helped over 20 families restore their credit and keep their homes and began online delivery using Wordpress on a Linux server
- Documented the money management coaching program into a 'ready to publish' manuscript

JOHN HECKBERT

johnheckbert@yahoo.ca ■ Cell: 416.918.6715 ■ linkedin.com/in/johnheckbert ■, Toronto, ON

 Established and implemented a retail focused lead generation program for Finbank Mortgage which resulted in over 300 new customers and \$8 million of new mortgage business

Management Consultant

2007 - 2009

SBR Global ◆ Two Global Eyes ◆ CommonVision ◆ ITSMF Canada

Within six months at each firm,

- Completely built the sales strategy and introduced the firms and their services to over 100 leading Canadian firms
- Created a contact database populated with <u>300+ new sector contacts</u>
- Re-established key senior-level relationships with <u>Hydro One, Sears Canada, Toronto Hydro, Powerstream, Enersource, Ontario Power Generation, Rogers Communications, Infrastructure Ontario and the Ontario Power Authority generating \$1 million of new business opportunities
 </u>
- Designed and implemented a web based retail sales strategy and infrastructure for an industry association allowing them to increase their educational product sales by 50% in the first year

Information Technology Management

1997 - 2007

Rogers Communications ♦ Ontario Hydro One ♦ Manulife ♦ John Hancock ♦ Ontario Power Generation

- Introduced new ITIL-based Problem Management and Incident Management processes into an underperforming business unit that eliminated 75% of service disruptions and reduced duration of service disruptions a further 75% within the first year
- Following Manulife's acquisition of John Hancock Financial, played a key leadership role in the creation and integration of a new consolidated Service Desk consisting of 5,500 IS staff supporting over 14,000 desktops and 160 servers across North America
- Introduced new standardized Problem Management, Change Management, Asset Management, Vendor Management and Escalation processes across 140 internal and external service delivery teams – new processes enhanced service performance, improved order provisioning, eliminating errors and reducing costs
- Successful integrated two disparate organizations, serving as the face and driving force behind the transition
- Led the construction project of 1 Data Centre and the Data Centre relocation projects for 3 companies

Applications/Automation Development (IT Operations Analyst)

1995 - 1997

- ◆ Rogers Communications ◆
- Designed, developed, implemented and supported the system and network automation initiarive, impacting all Rogers business units and technologies, including telephony
- Initial target of the initiative was to reduce the time required for a mainframe restart by 50% (from the original 38 minutes) – actual result was an 85% reduction
- Designed and developed applications to address operational deficiencies and improve transparency of the IT daily functioning to the business partners
- Tools included: Netview, HP Openview, CA-Unicenter, REXX, Fortran, Cicso Command Centre, RACF

PREVIOUS EXPERIENCE includes

Metropolitan Toronto Police Services – All police activities as assigned

EDUCATION

BrainStation – Diploma, Web Development **Project Management –** York University Executive Development **Bachelor of Arts** – Psychology, University of Waterloo

JOHN HECKBERT

johnheckbert@yahoo.ca ■ Cell: 416.918.6715 ■ linkedin.com/in/johnheckbert ■, Toronto, ON

INDUSTRY & COMMUNITY LEADERSHIP

Vice President, Communications – ITSMF, Upper Canada Region	2008 - 2009
Chapter President – International Service Club, Richmond Hill	2006 - 2009
Charter & Past President – Southern Ontario Tivoli Users Group	1997 - 2000
President, Ontario Chapter - International Assoc. for Computer Operations Management	1997 – 1998
Regional Rep Team Coach – Orangeville Soccer Club – Under 17 Bovs and U19 Girls	1995 – 1997